1millionwomen.com.au 2013-12-07

# 1 Million Women

**EXECUTIVE OVERVIEW**

YOUR PRIVACY: The 1 Million Women campaign and its parent organisation Australian Climate Coolers Limited (Climate Coolers), and their affiliates, recognise that your privacy is very important to you. Providing your personal information is an act of trust that we take very seriously, and we are committed to protecting your privacy. We undertake that we will not sell, trade, give or rent any of the personal information obtained from you to a third party.

INFORMATION: We acknowledge that we will collect and store information about you as part of the normal operation of this website, and we and/or our approved agents will use aggregated data thus collected to access campaign progress, to identify improvements, and to report internally and externally on the campaign’s achievements. Information volunteered by you, such as e-mail address, name, address and telephone number (not required by us), is used only for the purpose for which it was disclosed. We do not publish personally identifiable information collected through this website. In regard to our activity centre, carbon calculator, online census questionnaire, and other polls for campaign purposes, we will aggregate responses for research and reporting but will not disclose your personal responses to any third party.

COMMUNICATIONS TO YOU: In the normal course of our evolving campaign, we will also send you a range of updates on the campaign from time to time, and also ‘alerts’ and ‘offers’ and ‘specials’ including but not necessarily limited to: 1 Million Women campaign merchandise and projects; campaign-relevant partner and sponsor product and service opportunities including discount offers; new government programs and rebates; upcoming events, campaign questionnaires, polls and petitions etc . You can opt out of receiving such materials at any time (see Participant Choice section below)

PRINCIPLES: In this regard, we will act ethically and as evidence of this commitment, we will take reasonable steps to comply with a number of principles (see in greater detail below) in relation to the information you give to us about you.

AUTOMATIC RECORDING: We may automatically record details about any computer used to access our website (such as the IP address, domain name and browser type), the date and the time of access and details of information downloaded. This information is not capable of identifying you.

COOKIES: This website may use cookies. Cookies are pieces of information stored on an individual’s computer and are used for customising site information to improve user experience and tracking user navigation. If you are concerned about the use of cookies, you can set your browser to refuse cookies or warn you when cookies are being used.

SECURITY: We take all reasonable security measures to protect personal information from loss, unauthorised access or modification. We reserve the right to gather more extensive information about any attempted access to this website that raises security issues and, if appropriate, make disclosures to the relevant authorities.

POLICY UPDATING: This website will be continually improved and up-dated. This may change the way we manage personal information. The content of this internet Privacy Statement may be up-dated from time to time to reflect any changes.You should check this page periodically for changes to this Privacy Statement.

**FURTHER DETAIL**

**Collection**

1 Million Women and Climate Coolers collect the personal data that you volunteer on registering to join on our website [www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/), or through other forms, or by email.

This information will only be collected by lawful and fair means.

In order to register on the 1 Million Women website we require some basic information about you. We also allow you to provide additional non-required information on registration and at other times. Only information marked, as ‘required’ during registration is needed to use services on the website. This information is used for identification purposes and to contact you when necessary.

As you browse the 1 Million Women website we may log the IP address of your computer, session details, and domain name to evaluate which parts of the website you visit and how long you stay there. We do not link your computer’s IP address with any other information you have submitted to us. While a [www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) user’s session may be tracked, all users remain anonymous when tracked.

IP tracking information is aggregated with tracking data from all site visitors to measure number of visits, average time spent on the website, pages viewed, and to help diagnose problems with our server.

**Use and disclosure**

[www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) requires you to provide certain information about yourself in order to provide services to you. We will not rent, sell or exchange information about you to third parties (other than related parties) except where you consent, or except where you would expect the information to be disclosed, or except where we have indicated we may disclose; or except where we are legally obliged to disclose such information.

**Data quality**

[www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) will take reasonable steps to ensure that information we have about you is accurate, complete and up to date when we collect and use it.

**Data security**

[www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) will take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we hold about you is kept secure at all times.

[www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) will limit access to your personal information to employees and data processors, or approved researchers who are assisting the 1 Million Women campaign, that need it to carry out or to develop the service provided by us except where we inform you otherwise. Our employees and data processors are obliged to respect the confidentiality of clients’ and website visitors’ personal data. 1 Million Women and Climate Coolers will reinforce with other employees and any approved agents the policies and practices in relation to safeguarding personal information of clients and visitors, preventing its unauthorised access, use or disclosure, and ensuring its proper handling.

Our website has policies, rules and measures in place to protect the visitor’s personal data from:

  * Unauthorised access

  * Improper use

  * Alteration

  * Unlawful or accidental destruction

  * Accidental loss.

**Openness**

w[ww.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.climatecoolers.com/) will be honest and open with you about the type of personal information that is collected about you and the actual use of any such information. If when registering you select “Yes, please send me special offers and discounts”, by giving out your personal information, or filling in the entry or application form, you have consented to the use of this information in future, for marketing campaigns that 1 Million Women and Climate Coolers feel you may be interested in.

At any time you have the option to opt out from receiving any future marketing material by sending an email to [enquiries@www.1millionwomen.com.au](mailto:enquiries@www.1millionwomen.com.au) and requesting to opt out from newsletters.

**Access and correction**

If you provide us with satisfactory personal identification, such as your login details, [www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) will let you have access to the information we keep about you and give you the opportunity to have that information corrected if it is found to be incorrect.

Further, if [www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) is not able to release details of personal information to you, then we will provide you with reasons for any denial of access or correction.

**Anonymity**

You can access our web site home page and browse the public area of the 1 Million Women website without disclosing personal information.

[www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) will, wherever it is lawful and practicable, give you the option of not identifying yourself to us except where it is necessary to use our website services.

**Transfer of Data**

[www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) will take reasonable steps to ensure that if any information you give us about you will remain subject to the protection given by our Privacy Statement or another statute or binding scheme which is substantially similar to this Privacy Statement.

**Sensitive information**

[www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) will not collect information that is considered highly personal or highly sensitive about you. For example, information relating to your racial or ethnic origin, religious or philosophical beliefs, sexual orientation or in relation to your health will not be collected by us.

**Cookies**

[www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) uses cookies to hold session information, improve security during a visitor’s session online, ensure effective advertising tailored to the visitor’s needs, and provide you with your information.

We store the following information in cookies: your unique user ID

You can use your browser to disable cookies;  [www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) is not liable for any errors which may be encountered with the website as a result.

**Participant Choice**

By registering with [www.1millionwomen.com.au](http://www.1millionwomen.com.au/) you have chosen to receive promotional or marketing information from our web site or organisation and/or affiliates and alliances. At any time you can opt out from receiving such Information by sending a request to Opt Out using any of the following methods:

**Email  Address:**

****

**Coverage and Complaints**

Our Privacy Statement covers Australian Climate Coolers Limited (Climate Coolers) ABN 86 122 248 122 and the 1 Million Women website:

If you would like to make a complaint on the basis that you feel your privacy has been breached because we have failed to comply with this Privacy Statement, you should contact us using the following methods:

**Email Address:**
